bing.com 2014-02-24

# Bing Privacy Statement

Cookies & Similar TechnologiesCookies

When you use Bing services with a web browser, we will place one or more "cookies" on your machine. For example, Bing uses a cookie with a unique identifier known as the Search ID to operate the service and enable certain search features. If you sign into Bing or other Microsoft services using a Microsoft account, we will set or read one or more additional cookies. We use these cookies to operate Bing services and provide you a more relevant search experience. You can use your browser settings to remove or block cookies on your computer. 

We also use web beacons to help deliver cookies and compile analytics. These may include third-party web beacons, which are prohibited from collecting your personal information. 

Collecting Your InformationCollecting Your Information

When you use Bing services, Microsoft may collect many kinds of information in order to operate effectively and provide you the best products, services and experiences we can. We collect information when you register, sign in and use our sites and services. We also may get information from other companies. We collect this information in a variety of ways, including from web forms, technologies like cookies, web logging and software on your computer or other device.

When you conduct a search, Microsoft collects the following: 

  * Search term and time and date of your search 
  * IP address, browser configuration and approximate location 
  * Any unique identifiers contained in the cookies 

We store search terms (and the cookie IDs associated with search terms) separately from any account information that directly identifies the user, such as name, e-mail address, or phone numbers. We have technological safeguards in place designed to prevent the unauthorized correlation of this data and we remove the entirety of the IP address after 6 months, cookies and other cross session identifiers, after 18 months.

Bing provides search services to select partners and its users. Some examples include Yahoo! and Nokia. In order to provide these services, Bing services receive certain search related information from these partners that may include date, time, IP address, a unique identifier and other search related data.

How We Use Your Personal InformationUsing Your Information

Microsoft uses the information we collect to operate, improve and personalize the products and services we offer. We also may use the information to communicate with you, for example, informing you about your account and security updates.

For Bing services, we use this information to provide you with relevant search results. We also use the information we collect to maintain and improve the quality, security and integrity of our services. For example we may use this information for research purposes and to improve the relevancy of Bing search results. This information is also necessary in order to detect and protect against security threats such as botnet attacks, click fraud, worms, and other threats. 

Finally, as described in the Display of Advertising section of this document, we may use search query data for the purpose of personalizing the ads we display to you as you use our services or those of our advertising partners.

Reasons We Share Your Personal InformationSharing Your Information

Except as described in this privacy statement, we won’t disclose your personal information to a third party without your consent.

We may share some anonymized search query data with selected third parties for research purposes.

When you click on a link from a Bing search results page, the destination website will receive the standard information your browser sends to every web site you visit, including the URL of the site you came from.  Because the URL of the Bing search results page contains the text of the search query you entered, the destination website will be able to determine the search term you entered.

If your browser is enabled to allow pages to pre-load in the background for faster performance, Bing may use this functionality and your browser may preload page(s) in the background for faster results.  When your browser loads a page in the background, it will have the same effect as if you visited that page, including sending the Bing results page URL (which may contain your search query) and downloading any cookie files that page may set.  You can delete cookies using your browser settings.  Click [here](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=280122) for more information on how to delete cookies and to control pre-loading pages in Internet Explorer 11. 

Please see Other Important Privacy Information for additional details about when we may disclose information, including with Microsoft affiliates and vendors; when required by law or to respond to legal process; to combat fraud or protect our interest; or to protect lives.

Accessing Your Personal Information and Search HistoryAccessing Your Information

When using a web browser, you can access and manage your information, including Search History, on Bing through the preferences page. In Bing search, using the search terms you enter and the results you click, Search History provides an easy way to revisit the sites and searches you've used before. You may clear your search history from appearing on the site by following the steps provided in [see your search history](http://onlinehelp.microsoft.com/en-us/bing/ff808483.aspx "see your search history") (scroll down to "Clear search history"). Clearing your history removes it from the Search History service and prevents that history from being displayed on the site, but does not delete information from our standard search logs, which are retained and anonymized as described above. 

Bing Mobile, Maps and Location ServicesMobile and Location Services

If you have agreed to allow access to your location, the app may collect that information to provide more relevant experiences and enhanced features that rely on knowing your location, and to improve Microsoft products and services.  For example, we use your location to improve your search and mapping results, and provide you deals for local businesses.

  *  **Bing Search services and Bing Mobile applications:** The approximate location of your device will be sent to Microsoft along with search terms, time and date of your search and a unique identifier generated by the application. Refer to the documentation that came with your device for information about how to turn off location for an application.
  *  **"Check In” and “Reminders”:** When you sign into these services, Microsoft stores the approximate location of your device along with your Microsoft account. To disable access to your device’s location by these services, go to the settings menu of the Bing Search application and turn location to “Off.” If you are using a browser to access Bing Search services, refer to the browser documentation to disable sharing your location for sites visited on that browser.
  *  **Mapping features:** Features on Microsoft's sites and services are based in part on the Bing Maps service. When you submit information, such as an address to be viewed on a map, to the application, that application passes it to Bing Maps for processing.

Facebook PersonalizationFacebook Personalization

Bing uses Facebook Instant Personalization to provide a more relevant and useful search experience for Facebook users using your public information from Facebook. Facebook Instant Personalization is a program in which websites can check to see if you are actively logged into Facebook, and provide you with an enhanced experience that takes your Facebook social network into account, as permitted by your Facebook privacy settings. You can turn off these Instant Personalization features at any time by going to <http://www.facebook.com/help/?faq=204873389548151>.

 In addition, Bing search and Microsoft apps that use Bing services (also known as “Bing apps”) described in the Bing Apps section of this statement may also have features available that permit you to connect to Facebook to further personalize your experience on Bing search and to personalize your experience in Bing apps.  You can turn off these additional personalization features by going to <https://www.facebook.com/settings?tab=applications> and removing the Bing app.

Bing ApplicationsBing Applications

Microsoft apps that use Bing services (also known as “Bing apps”) provide you with enhanced features and convenient ways to access information such as weather forecasts, traffic reports or internet search results  (not all Microsoft applications or Bing features are available in every country).  Bing apps are available on a variety of platforms and services including apps preinstalled with Windows, apps created for the iOS, apps in the Microsoft Store, and as browser plug-ins and toolbars. 

When you install and use Bing apps, information about your computer and how you use the app, such as type and version of operating system, browser information and buttons you click, is collected and used by Microsoft in order to operate the Bing services and to help improve Bing and other Microsoft products and services. 

If you are using Bing Desktop or Bing Toolbar and choose to participate in the Bing Experience Improvement Program, we also collect additional information about how you use these specific Bing apps, including information about your searches within these apps. Additionally, when opted into the Bing Experience program on Bing Toolbar, we collect information about the addresses of the websites you visit.  

Lastly, some Bing apps provide the option to configure the application to use additional information from other Microsoft products and services, or from third parties.

ChildrenChildren

When a Microsoft site or service collects age information, it will block users under 13 or obtain consent from a parent or guardian before their child can use it. 

When consent is granted, the child’s account is treated much like any other account, including being able to communicate with other users. Parents can change or revoke consent as described in this privacy statement.

Display of AdvertisingAdvertising

Most of the online advertisements on Microsoft sites and services are displayed by Microsoft Advertising.  When we display online advertisements to you, we will place one or more cookies in order to recognize your computer when we display an ad to you.  Over time, we may gather information from the sites where we serve ads and use the information to help provide more relevant ads.

 **You may opt out of receiving targeted ads from Microsoft Advertising by visiting our   [Your privacy and Microsoft personalized ads](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=286759)**. For more information about how Microsoft Advertising collects and uses information, please see the [Microsoft Advertising Privacy Statement. ](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkID=248689)

Communication PreferencesCommunications

You can stop the delivery of future promotional email from Microsoft sites and services by following the specific instructions in the email you receive.  You also have the option of proactively making choices about the receipt of promotional email, telephone calls and postal mail from Microsoft by visiting and signing in to the [Promotional Communications Manager](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=243191 "Promotional Communications Manager").

Microsoft AccountMicrosoft Account

Microsoft account (formerly known as Windows Live ID and Microsoft Passport) is a service that allows you to sign into Microsoft products, web sites and services, as well as those of select Microsoft partners.When you create a Microsoft account, we ask you to provide certain information. When you sign into a site or service using your Microsoft account, we collect certain information in order to verify your identity on behalf of the site or service, to protect you from malicious account usage, and to protect the efficiency and security of the Microsoft account service. We also send certain information to a site or service you have signed into with your Microsoft account. 

To view additional details about Microsoft account, including how to create and use a Microsoft account, how to edit account information, and how we collect and use information relating to a Microsoft account, please click on Learn More. 

Other Important Privacy InformationOther Information

Learn more about

  * Non-Microsoft services that use Bing search
  * Why and with whom we share or disclose personal information
  * Protecting the security of personal information
  * Where we store and process information
  * Changes to our privacy statements
  * How to contact us
